HIEN TRONG TRAN

WEB DEVELOPER

https://tranhien-portfolio.vercel.app 🙀 https://github.com/hientt1803

I'm a front-end developer with 6 months of experience in React.js (Next.js) and Java (spring boot). I have worked as a front-end and back-end developer on large and small projects such as Managing a programming teaching center, Notion clone, Blog website...

SKILL

- Proficient: React.js(Next.js),
 Tailwind, Bootstrap, SCSS,
 Responsive, Java(Core, Spring Boot), SQL.
- Familiar: Redux, typescript, Java Swing, PHP(Laravel), NodeJS, MongoDB, MySQL, Figma, Firebase.
- Tools: Figma, Git, Trello, Junit4, TestNG (basic).

LANGUAGE

English - Top Notch 3

EDUCATION

FPT Polytechnic College Can Tho (August 2021 - December 2023)

- **Major**: Software Development
- Status: graduated
- Excellent student in year (2023)

EXPERIENCE

Full-stack developer | Manage programing teaching center | 4-person group project

Development | September 2023 - December 2023

- **Tech stack:** Java (Spring Boot), RESTful APIs, React.js, Bootstrap, SCSS, SQL Server.
- GitHub: https://github.com/alexnguyen03/f4education
- **Project purpose:** Created a web application to managing a programming teaching center where they can sold and teach programing with most popular technology.
- Responsibilities:
 - Back-end: Develop backend systems/APIs
 - Fron-end: Create and handle functions shopping cart, checkout, statistics, manager attendance, question banking's, certificate, import export excel file.
- Achieve: How to use React and Java spring boot, MVC, Spring JPA, Restful APIs to build a whole website management a programing teaching center.

Backend intern at Can Tho University software center (CUSC) for 11 week

Development | September 2023 - November 2023

- Tech stack: PHP (Laravel), MySQL, Swager.
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/kellyfire611/cusc-his-v3-api
- Project purpose: Create a APIs with Laravel 10 and MySQL for website like WordPress where people can drag and drop template available and building there own website.
- Responsibilities: Create whole APIs for website, create a dynamic control for render and download office document(Word, Excel, PowerPoint).
- Achieve: learned how to working with Laravel, MySQL, Docker, MVC and Module structure, working with dynamic render office document (Word, Excel, PDF)

Full-stack Developer | Notion clone | personal project

Development | January 2024

- Tech stack: Next.js, Tailwind, typescript, convex, clerk
- **GitHub:** https://github.com/hientt1803/notion-clone
- Project purpose: Create a taking note app where people can

note there activity, stories,... and publish them to there friend.

- Responsibilities: Development and deploy website.
- **Achieve:** Learned working with a real-time Database Convex, create custom hooks, build a complex logic UI and functions.
- Website URL: https://modern-note-taking-app.vercel.app/

Full-stack Developer | Blog website | personal project

Development | January 2024

- Tech stack: Next.js, SCSS, Tailwind, MongoDB, Prisma, firebase
- **GitHub:** https://github.com/hientt1803/augentern-blog-app
- **Project purpose:** Create an blog website where people can login, write blog, share there stories, like, comment other post.
- Responsibilities: Development and deploy website.
- **Achieve**: Learned how to create a what blog app be with Next.js, Context API and MongoDB to display, create post, like, share,...